Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Rufus Henry Fitzgerald, Administrative Files, 1945-1955 UA.2.10.1945-1955
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- War Emergency, Armed Forces Institute, 1943-1945 (Box 50, Folder 337)
  Professors who are in the Army; Shrivenham American University, Shrivenham, England, Term II, October 1945; Army University Study Center
- War Emergency, Civilian Defense, 1941-1943 (Box 50, Folder 339)
  Director appointed, 1943; Organization chart of the city of Pittsburgh Civilian Defense; State Council of Defense – College Division; "School and College Civilian Morale Service", 1941; State Council of Defense rule governing blackout, 1943; University Civilian Defense Program
- War Emergency, Enlisted Reserve (Box 50, Folder 339)
  Army Specialized Training Program; Navy College Program
- War Emergency, Faculty Conscription (Box 51, Folder 340)
  Deferment letters for Faculty and Stafft; Memorandum on occupational deferments
- War Emergency, War Manpower Commission (Box 51, Folder 341)
  Preliminary announcement of the Army Specialized Training Program; clippings
- War Emergency, Goodyear Aircraft Training Program (Box 51, Folder 342)
- War Emergency, 3 ½ year High School students, 1942-1944 (Box 51, Folder 343)
- War Emergency, Japanese Students (Box 51, Folder 345, Folder 344)
- War Emergency, Key Center of Information (Box 51, Folder 345)
- War Emergency, Meteorology Courses (Box 51, Folder 346)
- War Emergency, Navy R.O.T.C. (Box 51, Folder 347)
- War Emergency, Navy Medical and Dental Units (Box 51, Folder 348)
- War Emergency, Petroleum Products Testing and Inspection (Box 51, Folder 349)
- War Emergency, Physical Fitness Program (Box 51, Folder 350)
- War Emergency, Committee on Emergency Research, 1942-1944 (Box 51, Folder 351)
  Progress Reports, Contracts, Memoranda
- War Emergency, Student conscription, 1940-1944 (Box 51, Folder 352)
- War Emergency, Student War Loans (Box 51, Folder 353)
- War Emergency, Student Transportation and Gas Rationing Committee (Box 51, Folder 354)
- War Emergency, Army Air Corps (1) (Box 52, Folder 355)
- War Emergency, Army Air Corps (2) (Box 52, Folder 356)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Reserve Program, June 1943-March 1945 (Box 52, Folder 357)
  Correspondence, Manuals, Curricula
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (1), November 1943-March 1945 (Box 52, Folder 358)
  Course listings, Faculty, Students
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (2), November 1943-March 1945 (Box 52, Folder 359)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Program, September 1943-October 1943 (Box 53, Folder 360)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Program, June 1943-August 1943 (Box 53, Folder 361)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Program, December 1942-May 1943 (Box 53, Folder 362)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Program,Contract material (Box 53, Folder 363)
- War Emergency, Army Specialized Training Program, Medicine and Dentistry (Box 54, Folder 364)
- Weber, John, 1943-1955 (Box 54, Folder 365)
  Secretary of the University; Memos; Correspondence concerning costs; Buildings; Excerpts from Minutes of Board of Trustees, 1952-53 concerning money; Memo concerning Bellefield Boiler Plant; Three weeks vacation for certain long term secretaries, 1950; List of Senate bills involving Pitt, 1949; Senate bills; Proposed distribution of space in Thaw Hall, 1947; Westinghouse television tower; see also 3/4/1A
- Weber, John, 1938-1943 (Box 54, Folder 365)
- Western State Psychiatric Institute and Clinic, 1947-1954 (Box 54, Folder 367)
  Memos; Organization chart; Relationship with the University
- Westinghouse Electric Corporation (Box 54, Folder 368)
  Scholarships by Westinghouse; George Westinghouse Centennial forum; George Westinghouse
- W (General) (Box 54, Folder 369)
  White House Conference on Education; John Hay Whitney Foundation; Who's Who (has some biographies); "The Kaiser Book", ed. By Max Herzig – gift of Dr. Samuel H. Williams, 1954; Mildred Walters; Charles Wertz; Western Theological Seminary; Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Program
- Small Pamphlets (Box 54, Folder 370)
  American Council on Education Studies: Higher Education cooperates in national defense, 1941; Higher Education and the war, 1942; Organizing higher education for national defense, 1941; Sound educational credit for military experience, 1943
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority, 1948-1949 (Box 55, Folder unknown container)
  Applications for the position of Director (Fitzgerald was Chairman of the Authority)
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority, 1949 (Box 55, Folder 372)
  Applications – Engineer
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 55, Folder 373)
  Architects; Preliminary estimates, August 7, 1950 Prepared by Ramp Buildings Corp.; Correspondence
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 55, Folder 374)
  Engineers
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 55, Folder 375)
  Financing; RHF as chairman of the Authority signed Agreement between the Authority and the City; correspondence concerning sale of bonds; Misc. correspondence
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 55, Folder 376)
  House Bill no. 542; In the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania. Western District. Brief in behalf of the Public Parking Authority of Pittsburgh and the City of Pittsburgh. No 115, March term, 1948; Pennsylvania House Bill no. 542, 1947; Parking Authority Law (abstract, 1947)
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 55, Folder 377)
  McNeil; Correspondence; Includes some plans; Agreement with Hoffman & Crumpton, registered architects
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority, 1950-1951 (Box 55, Folder 378)
  Meeting minutes and Reports
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 56, Folder 379)
  Meetings & reports, 1947-49; Correspondence; Report on Six Proposed Parking Facilities, 1948; Summary report of Authority's activities to date, may 1, 1949; Minutes of meetings
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 56, Folder 380)
  Ch. Fitzgerald resigned from Parking Authority, 1951; Certificate from the Committee; Appointment to Authority, 1947 – correspondence
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 56, Folder 381)
  Real Estate; Correspondence
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 56, Folder 382)
  Treasurer, 1948-51
- Pittsburgh Public Parking Authority (Box 56, Folder 383)
  Miscellaneous; Clipping: Miss Alpern quits Parking Authority; Examples of other parking plazas; "Allegheny county Farmers Market" (summary & conclusions, by Wayne A. Lee, 1947); Pamphlet: Parking study of the Pittsburgh central business district, 1945-46
- University of Pennsylvania, Division of Placement Research, First Annual Report, 1953 (Box 57, Folder 384)
  First annual report, 1950-51; presentation copy for Fitzgerald for service on the Committee on Research and Publications, University of Pennsylvania
- Survey of administrative management of the University of Pittsburgh, by Cresap, McCormick & Paget for Chancellor Fitzgerald, April 14, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 385)
  "Cresap Report"
- Speeches, 1939-1945 (Box 60, Folder 388)
  Includes list of speeches for Folders 387-388
- Speeches, 1946-1955 (Box 60, Folder 388)
- Graduate School of Public Health (Box 60, Folder 390)
  Estimated space requirements for new school; conference on methods in public health research, May 10-11, 1950 – program; degrees for students pursuing studies in public health; Pre-catalogue, October, 1949; Correspondence, Parran-McEllroy concerning appointments to be made; Instructional and research interests in public health; Notes on recruitment of personnel; Agreement of lease – Municipal Hospital. Correspondence 10/20/1948-9/18/1950.
- Graduate School of Public Health (Box 60, Folder 391)
  A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust gift; memos of conferences; letter concerning progress in the 14 months since the gift; minutes of Board of Trustees 9/21/1948 and 12/14/1948; copy of deed of gift in trust; news releases
- Graduate School of Public Health (Box 60, Folder 392)
  Preliminary procedures 1/23/1948-5/9/1950; Concerning Logan Armory; blueprint plans of property from Real Estate Co. of Pittsburgh; Excerpts from Summary Report of 10 schools of public health 1946-47; Report – The organization and operation of a university medical center with particular reference to the University of Pittsburgh; Mayor Lawrence's speech 5/5/1948; notes on a cooperative arrangement – Dr. Lowell J. Reed; statement on research in natural sciences; confidential reports.
- Graduate School of Public Health, Personnel (Box 60, Folder 393)
  Biographical notes on faculty: Atwater, Shepard, Reed, Ciocco, Cox, Crabtree, Dingle, Hatch, Densen, Hamman, Johnson, Robert E., Kammer, Lichty, Smith Charles Edward, Sterner
- Graduate School of Public Health, Thomas Parran (Box 60, Folder 394)
  Address by Fosdick at the inauguration of Raymond Edens as President of Duke University, 10/21/1949 (Parran attended for the University); Parran's out-of-the-city schedules 1949-50; Report by Parran to Adolph Schmidt 2/28/1949; Parran Curriculum Vitae.
- Graduate School of Public Health, Parran Scholarship Fund, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 395)
- Graduate School of Public Health, Municipal Hospital (Box 60, Folder 396)
  Temporary quarters for the School
- Graduate School of Public Health, Public Health Law Project (Box 60, Folder 397)
  Statement of Organization and Procedure; Proposal for the codification of Public Health Laws 1948-49
- Graduate School of Public Health, Finance (Box 60, Folder 398)
  Review of investments, March 1949, April 1949, September 1949; Memo concerning federal aid to schools of public health; copy of U.S. Senate bill on aid to medical education; Memo of transactions 12/10/1948 regarding Mellon gift
- Graduate School of Public Health, Clippings (Box 60, Folder 399)
  Moved to UA RG 90/41-e
- Honorary Degrees (Box 61)
  Honorary Degrees awarded to Fitzgerald from Washington & Jefferson College 1948; Carnegie Institute of Technology 1947; Stetson University 1956; Alfred University 1948; Allegheny College 1955; Grove City College 1949; University of Pittsburgh 1955
- Congratulatory Letters to Fitzgerald concerning his Retirement as Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, 1955 (Box 61, Volume 1)